Okay, we're ready for a completely
different kind of orchestration. Now, I
will just mention that front end, even
though we've done a checkout main front
end still has lots of stuff in it
because this is git ignored stuff. So,
I'm just going to delete this whole
folder like that and create a new front
end folder so that we're definitely
starting from scratch and not giving any
hints away. I'm also going to come into
claude and make sure that our
settings.json, JSON. If we look at this,
hang on. Move down. The Yes, it has some
of these plugins, but it does not have
the setting, the experimental setting.
Let's clear the screen and start again.
And also, we'll we will stop Claude code
from running right here. That is a wrap
on that previous version. Clear the
screen. Okay. Now, let me introduce you
to the second way that we are going to
try and go crazy along our journey
together. I've mentioned a few times
there's a technique called STDD specd
driven design and STD is is about having
plugins or tools or processes which
walks through the process of putting
together a spec and then executing on
that spec. And in some ways the feature
dev plugin that we used is a nod to
that. There are some more formal ones
that go through a more rigorous process.
And there was a time when that was a big
deal with claude code and it seems to be
less so now because it feels like it's a
slightly laborious approach and you can
give up a little bit more and just let
it run with it more. And there is now a
new thing that's come up not that new
anymore but but pretty new which is seen
as a sort of natural evolution of
specdriven design which is spec driven
design coupled with this more radical
kind of orchestration framework. And
there is this approach that isn't just
for CL code. It's for any of these CLIs.
And it's one that goes by the name GSD.
And uh GSD stands for something which I
will bring up. And you can see it
visually here, but I but I'm not going
to say it. Uh and and here it is. So GSD
stands for get done as it says right
there in the repo. This is where it is.
And uh it is as it says lightweight.
It's what they call meta prompting which
is like a sort of something that you can
prompt that then is then controlling a
set of pre-built prompts context
engineering and specd driven development
stdd for clude code open code and Gemini
CLI so any of those three and it's
particularly it's it's looking to solve
context rot that was its initial premise
it's about trying to make sure that you
manage context really well and that you
don't get this kind of quality
degradation that we've all felt as the
context window starts to fill up. So
that was a big part of the problem it
set out to solve. Um and uh yeah it's um
luckily it works on all platforms and
this is the way to set it up and when
you do that when we run this command uh
we will get this this screen and it's
where we can choose to install it and
this is where we will be able to uh to
to drive this process. Um if you know
clearly what you want this will build it
for you. No BS, uh, says someone
unnamed. Um, I've done spec kit, opensp
spec, and taskmaster. This has produced
the best results for me. These three are
the more traditional specd driven design
approaches. If you want to look them up
and and have a shot at them, too, then
then you should do so. By far my most
powerful addition to claw code, says
somebody. Uh, literally just gets done.
Okay. uh and uh then uh you can you can
read more about the backstory behind it
before we dig in and we'll just read a
little bit more about it. I would
encourage you to go to this GitHub link
which I will of course put in the
resources. Vibe coding is a bad
reputation. You describe what you want.
AI generates code. You get inconsistent
garbage that falls apart at scale. Uh I
think that that is predates the November
inflection point. uh but still you get
you get that for big enough projects
still perhaps if you don't manage things
carefully with documents and so on but
GSE is designed to fix that it's the
context engineering layer that makes
cloud code reliable um it's for people
who can describe what they want and have
it built correctly without pretending
they're running a 50 person engineering
org
uh so we will now do this and they
recommend skip permissions mode running
claude with this. It's how it's intended
to be used. Stopping to approve date and
get commit 50 times defeats the purpose.
The alternative is to add granular
permissions. Uh so um all right. Uh we
are there's also it's got a set of
different commands you can do like /gs
GSD map codebase and so on. But but uh
uh and it goes through the the different
steps right here which we will carry out
in a sec. Okay. So without further ado,
let's make ourselves a new branch. a get
checkout minus B uh GSD
uh with sorry we'll call it finally GSD
just to avoid any confusion finally GSD
okay and now we will uh we will we will
execute that command to install this
okay yes
and there we go which runtime we like to
install it for for clawed code one.
Where would you like to install it?
Global V local this claude this project
only two. Done. Okay. So you can see a
bunch of stuff has been created here.
It's created. It's basically added in
agents commands the this folder that
we'll learn more about in a second and
and hooks. So, it's like a sort of in a
way this installer has done something
similar to installing a plug-in in that
it's just put all of this stuff right
here for us and we're ready to go.
Launchcloud code and run /gsd colon
help. Uh so, uh exciting, huh? Uh but
first, let's look at the docs one more
time. So, I would describe GSD as being
similar to the agent teams concept that
we've just worked with, but more
opinionated. It's something where it's
got more more constructs around it
designed to sort of put put you into a
particular way of doing it. I'm not
going to run it on dangerously skip
permissions mode. Uh if if I were to do
that, I would do it on the sandbox as we
had established before, but I'm happy to
be approving as we go. So, the way
you're meant to do it is by by going
through a number of different commands.
GSD new project is where you start
things going and uh uh it's going to to
uh to to uh initialize it will spawn
parallel agents to analyze the stack
conventions and then it knows the
codebase. So that's who we'll start then
GSD discuss is where you shape the
implementation as it says then GSD plan
is where you you go through and you you
plan a phase then GSD execute. then GSD
verify and then you do it for the next
milestone. We only have one milestone
and there is also a quick mode that that
does that does all of this if you don't
need the planning but we will go through
doing it this way. Then it's got a quick
sort of why it works. And the the main
point that this this stresses is that
first of all they've really focused on
the prompts on getting good strong
prompts. And secondly that they they
they preset the agents as well for this
but also importantly they they have got
um documentation
um that um hang on I'm just looking
through these these are the commands
again that it's explaining. You've got
the new project discuss phase plan phase
execute verify. You've got an audit
milestone, complete milestone, new
milestone.
Uh and uh this is some of the uh the the
other commands that you would get used
to managing phases and sessions. The
important thing to know is that it
produces a bunch of different um files
and these files are all um managed uh
for for us and that it's the files is
where it maintains the state of
everything that's going on. It's got a
fixed structure of markdown files that
it uses in order to track progress
through these different steps. So it is,
as I say, a sort of opinionated
structure around having multiple agents
work on your project. And here is the
file structure that it uses. It has
these files project MD, research,
requirements, road map, state, plan,
summary, to-dos. So it does all of this
for you. Um, and uh it's then got this
multi- aent orchestration uh at each
stage. These are the different agents
and and how they work. So have a read
through this, learn more about how this
is going to work. We will keep track of
the different commands that we're going
to run and then we're going to go
through and do this right now. And it's
worth mentioning that the the uh this
the author of this project is something
of a of a celebrity. It is a uh EDM an
electronic dance musician Kotashi is
based in LA uh who is behind this and
who's obviously made it into something
with a big following uh as is clear from
from its GitHub stars. Uh but let's get
into it. Let's uh let's start Claude. Um
up comes Claude and Claude has lots of
stuff. If we do SLC context we will see
uh presumably yes lots of GSD stuff in
there. Very nice. Uh, and uh, I wonder
whether we should remove context. And I
think we leave it. We leave everything
else exactly as is. We'll leave the rest
of the setup. Let's see what this has
done to the context. Looks fine. Um,
okay. And, uh, let's also do slash usage
just to see where I was. Remember last
time I was at 0, 8, and two. And now
let's write this down. After that first
experiment, we're at 8% used, 9% of the
current week, and 2% uh of the current
week still for Sonnet because I've been
using Opus. All right. Um I think that
we may be ready to start our GSD
process. Just in case we have to get
back to this point, let me just do a
quick uh get add dot just get that in
there. Get commit minus m start of GSD
process. So we'll have that all in now.
Then let's go back to here again and
let's run the first command which is
going to be slashgsd
colon new dash project. Here we go. And
we're running that. And it's doing some
stuff. It's reading the workflows
questioning UI brand projects.
Okay. Okay, I can see that it's got the
uh different models. It looks like it's
using Sonnet in a few places. Um I
detected. Would you like to map the code
first? Yes. One. We will say yes. We
will let it do the mapping.
Use skill. Yes. I should probably press
two. Then I press one. Um this is where
it would tell you that that we should
have done dangerously skip permissions.
We should have been in yolo mode. Uh but
it seems to be doing fine.
We will let it do its thing. Spawning
four mapper agents in parallel. See
everything that's going on. And this is
using of course sub agents. Um it is
using uh the sub agent functionality
rather than the new claude teams
functionality which makes sense. We'd be
doing uh we this is an alternative to
using claude's agent teams. Uh so it's
now running those agent the mapper
agents in parallel while they map out
the existing codebase. There's not much
to it. That's just the market data part,
but hopefully it's also reading the
documentation, which is super important.
And I will see you back when we are
ready to discuss the phase and begin.
Okay, so it's done the codebase mapping.
It's built a bunch of markdown files.
Hopefully, it was re reviewing the
planning documents we already have. I
imagine it was. It's in its memory for
sure. And now it's continuing with GSD
new project. And now it's got some
questions. What do you want to build? So
um before we do that I just want to make
sure that we we're on a level playing
field. I think by default it uses sonnet
for the development and I want it to use
opus otherwise we be be off to a
disadvantage and I believe the way I do
that is with /gsd colon settings. So let
me just quickly run this now and just
see uh how this works.
Uh
and so that then I can set it so that it
uses the right quality model. Here we
go. Which which uh model do we want? Um
we want to be number one. It says
balance is recommended but we want to
use number one quality. At least I want
to use that. You can use balance or
budget. I want to be on quality because
I want to be uh be fair about it. one
spawn plan researcher. Uh, that's um,
yes. Spawn plan checker. Yes. Execution
verifier. Yes. Excellent. Submit
answers. Done. Okay. So, that was nice.
An interactive way of setting the
settings. Yes. Okay.
Excellent. All right. I think it's time
for us to actually kick off our